<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Core JAVA (OOPS) on Code World</title>
    <link>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core JAVA (OOPS) on Code World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 18:16:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Module 4</title>
      <link>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 06:38:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-4/</guid>
      <description>Model-view-controller pattern The model-view-controller (MVC) pattern is a design pattern that separates an application into three components: the model, the view, and the controller. The model represents the data and business logic of the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module 3</title>
      <link>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 07:15:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-3/</guid>
      <description>Inheritance Inheritance is a fundamental concept in OO design where a class is based on another class, absorbing its attributes and behaviors and enhancing them. Inheritance allows programmers to create classes that are built upon existing classes, enabling code reusability and the addition of new features to existing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulation, Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 20:37:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-2/</guid>
      <description>Object-Oriented Programming Tutorial Object-oriented programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm that organizes data and behavior into reusable units called objects. Objects have attributes (data) and methods (functions) that operate on the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Data Types</title>
      <link>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 18:27:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arnab7070.github.io/sections/oops/module-1/</guid>
      <description>What is an abstract data type? An abstract data type (ADT) is a mathematical model for data types. It specifies the operations that can be performed on the data, but it does not specify how the data is stored or implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
